<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Workshops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/13-accesing-a-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/13-accesing-a-workshop/</guid>
      <description>The training portal service in Educates provides a gateway for accessing one or more workshops deployed to the Kubernetes cluster. If required, you can have more than one training portal service, with each providing access to a different set of workshops.&#xA;The training portal service can be configured to require simple authentication or access can be anonymous. The user interface provided by the training portal is designed to be basic and was originally intended to provide a quick way to provide access to a set of workshops for ad-hoc training, or use in conference booths for workshops or demos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authoring Workshops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/20-authoring-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/20-authoring-workshops/</guid>
      <description>You can use Educates to deploy workshops published by others, but to get the most from Educates you are more likely going to want to create your own workshops. You could also use it to create a simple mechanism to deploy application demos or test environments.&#xA;To create the skeleton for a new workshop using the CLI, run the command:&#xA;command: educates new-workshop lab-demo-workshop --title &amp;#34;Demo Workshop&amp;#34; --description &amp;#34;Workshop to demo use of Educates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning up the environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/16-test-cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/16-test-cleanup/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s now do some cleanup before we proceed to create our own Educates workshop.&#xA;The following commands will delete the workshop and the training portal that were created and will clear both terminals.&#xA;command: educates delete-workshop -f https://github.com/vmware-tanzu-labs/lab-k8s-fundamentals/releases/latest/download/workshop.yaml cascade: true command: educates delete-portal cascade: true clear NOTE: You might have noticed that last command you didn&amp;rsquo;t need to click it, as it was configured to automatically execute upon completion of the previous command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clickable Actions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/03-clickable-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/03-clickable-actions/</guid>
      <description>The name of the CLI for Educates is as one might expect, called educates. Running the CLI with no arguments will yield help on the major top level commands and command groups. Run the command in the terminal of the workshop session.&#xA;command: educates If this is your first experience with Educates you may have typed in the command manually, this however is not necessary and demonstrates the first bit of magic that Educates provides to make your workshops simpler for your users to work through.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cluster Installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/10-cluster-create/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/10-cluster-create/</guid>
      <description>The name of the Educates CLI is educates, and there&amp;rsquo;s flavors of the CLI for MacOS and Linux, both AMD64 and ARM64, which can be found in the project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repository&#xA;To install into an existing Kubernetes cluster the CLI command which needs to be used is:&#xA;educates admin cluster install Before running this command an appropriate configuration file needs to be created.&#xA;For installation of Educates into the virtual cluster created for this workshop session we will use the following configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cluster Installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/11-educates-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/11-educates-install/</guid>
      <description>With the configuration created we are ready to perform the installation by running the CLI command:&#xA;command: educates admin cluster install --config vcluster-config.yaml cooldown: .INF NOTE: This command will take some time to finish. Keep reading while the installation is performed.&#xA;Using the Carvel tools linked into the educates CLI binary, this will download the Educates package files (using vendir), customize the package YAML files using our configuration (using ytt), resolve the container images used and pin the versions (using kbld), and finally deploy everything to Kubernetes (using kapp).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Definition of a workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/15-definition-of-a-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/15-definition-of-a-workshop/</guid>
      <description>The Workshop is a Kubernetes custom resource that defines, amongst other:&#xA;Name and description T-shirt size for the associated namespace&amp;rsquo;s resources (Memory and Cpu) Security enforcement mechanism The location of the content of the workshop The capabilities and it&amp;rsquo;s configuration that the workshop will have Console (Terminals) Editor Slides Dashboards Docker Registry &amp;hellip; Kubernetes objects definitions that will need to be created along with the session Read the documentation if you want to know more about the Workshop resource</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy the Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/23-deploy-the-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/23-deploy-the-workshop/</guid>
      <description>To deploy the workshop from the current directory we now need to run:&#xA;command: educates deploy-workshop This is similar to how we deployed a previously published workshop except that since we are running it out of the directory for the workshop it will use the version of the workshop we just published to the local image registry.&#xA;Hop back over to the web browser window where the training portal was running and refresh the page, or once again run:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Cluster</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/01-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/01-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>The full Educates training platform requires a Kubernetes cluster in which to run. There&amp;rsquo;s more options, but we&amp;rsquo;re going to focus on the most common one, running Educates on a Kubernetes cluster.&#xA;Educates provides an opinionated installer to get you up and running on many flavours of Kubernetes clusters which include, Kind to run Educates on your own computer, or a hosted Kubernetes cluster such as EKS(AWS), GKE (GCP) or AKS (Azure).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manually Updating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/25-manually-updating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/25-manually-updating/</guid>
      <description>As demonstrated, the basic lifecyle for updating workshop content is to make any modifications, publish the workshop files as an OCI image to an image registry, and then create a new workshop session to see any changes.&#xA;When making lots of small changes it is possible to short circuit this process and use one of two mechanisms for making updates in a running workshop session.&#xA;The first of these still entails re-publishing the workshop files, but we can avoid the need to create a new workshop session by manually pulling down the changes into the current live workshop session.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Packaging Mechanism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/02-packaging-mechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/02-packaging-mechanism/</guid>
      <description>Numerous packaging and installation mechanisms exist for applications to be deployed to a Kubernetes cluster. Probably the most well known is Helm templates. For Educates, we use an alternative packaging and installation mechanism utilizing the Carvel tool set.&#xA;The Carvel tool set consists of a number of different tools which perform tasks such as vendoring (vendir), YAML templating (ytt), container image resolution and pinning (kbld), and Kubernetes application deployment (kapp).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing Workshops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/22-publishing-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/22-publishing-workshops/</guid>
      <description>To deploy the workshop we first need to publish it to a place where Educates will be able to download the workshop files at runtime.&#xA;Educates supports different mechanisms for hosting of the workshop files, including:&#xA;Hosting workshop files as an OCI image on an image registry. Hosting workshop files as a tar/zip archive on a web server. Hosting workshop files on a hosted Git repository (eg., GitHub). In other words, unlike many other SaaS based training platforms, you are not required to edit your workshop content in the platforms web interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realtime Updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/26-realtime-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/26-realtime-updates/</guid>
      <description>The second option for updating workshop content within the running workshop session involves a bit more magic.&#xA;To demonstrate this mechanism run the command:&#xA;command: educates serve-workshop --patch-workshop Exit the running instance of the demo workshop you have running in your other web browser window and start a new workshop session. Confirm you can see the same workshop instructions you had previously.&#xA;Make some more changes to the workshop instructions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure of a Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/21-structure-of-a-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/21-structure-of-a-workshop/</guid>
      <description>The workshop template when used creates the following files in the top level directory:&#xA;README.md - A file telling everyone what the workshop is about. Replace the current content provided in the sample workshop with your own. Key sub directories and the files contained within them are:&#xA;workshop - Directory under which your workshop files reside. workshop/content - Directory under which your workshop instructions resides. The files here follow Hugo content rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/12-testing-the-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/12-testing-the-installation/</guid>
      <description>To test that the installation was successful we can deploy a workshop. For this we will use a previously published workshop by running the command:&#xA;command: educates deploy-workshop -f https://github.com/vmware-tanzu-labs/lab-k8s-fundamentals/releases/latest/download/workshop.yaml To access the training portal service and browse the workshops hosted by it, run the command:&#xA;command: educates browse-workshops When the training portal service is ready, this should automatically open a new web browser window. Unfortunately though this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work reliably when using the command inside the terminal of an Educates workshop session due to browser popup restrictions, it should however work were you running it in a terminal on your local machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The training portal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/14-the-training-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/14-the-training-portal/</guid>
      <description>The Training Portal is a Kubernetes custom resource, so one can use Kubernetes client to get details about the resource:&#xA;command: kubectl get trainingportal Or the full yaml with all the configuration it contains:&#xA;session: 2 command: kubectl get trainingportal educates-cli -o yaml The trainingportal defines runtime configuration for each workshop that exposes, like maximum number of sessions, duration for the workshop, idle time to be considered abandoned, and many more as well as the url and credentials to access the portal in different ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updating Instructions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/24-updating-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/24-updating-instructions/</guid>
      <description>To update the workshop instructions open up the editor on the workshop overview page found in the workshop/content directory.&#xA;file: ~/lab-demo-workshop/workshop/content/00-workshop-overview.md Select the paragraph describing the workshop:&#xA;file: ~/lab-demo-workshop/workshop/content/00-workshop-overview.md text: &amp;#34;^This is .*$&amp;#34; isRegex: true and replace it with a better description of this workshop.&#xA;file: ~/lab-demo-workshop/workshop/content/00-workshop-overview.md text: | This demo workshop is intended to demonstrate how awesome Educates is. After having made the change re-publish the workshop files so that they will be picked up for any freshly created workshop sessions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Definition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/30-workshop-definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/30-workshop-definition/</guid>
      <description>The publishing lifecycle as described pertains to the workshop files used for workshop instructions as well as any other files, scripts or applications used within the workshop session. These will be downloaded for each distinct workshop session.&#xA;When the workshop was deployed using the educates deploy-workshop command, the configuration of the workshop environment was dictated by the workshop definition. This is a Kubernetes resource which describes where the workshop files can be found, as well as what capabilities are required for a workshop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/00-workshop-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/00-workshop-overview/</guid>
      <description>Educates is a system for hosting interactive workshop environments in Kubernetes, or a local docker environment. It can be used for self paced or supervised workshops. It can also be useful where you need to package up demos of applications hosted in Kubernetes.&#xA;In this workshop you will learn the basics of how to install Educates using the CLI and how to author a workshop. A you will do all the learning through Educates, which means that what you see is what you can get (and more).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Summary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/99-workshop-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshop/content/99-workshop-summary/</guid>
      <description>You have reached the end of this workshop. We hope you have seen the great value a tool like Educates can provide to you, and how easy it is to author workshops.&#xA;For more information about Educates see:&#xA;Educates Documentation Educates GitHub Repository If you have questions about Educates or need help installing or using it, you can reach out to the developers of Educates and other Educates users in the #educates Slack channel hosted under the Kubernetes Slack Community.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
